<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://codetricity.github.io/sc2-public-code-examples/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://codetricity.github.io/sc2-public-code-examples/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-26T12:57:46-08:00</updated><id>https://codetricity.github.io/sc2-public-code-examples/feed.xml</id><title type="html">RICOH THETA WebAPI Community Documents</title><subtitle>RICOH THETA WebAPI community documents.  Use a HTTP API  to communicate with a RICOH THETA 360 camera.  Works from mobile and desktop devices. https://theta360.guide</subtitle><entry><title type="html">RICOH THETA WebAPI Versions</title><link href="https://codetricity.github.io/sc2-public-code-examples/api/versions,/s,/m15,/sc/2021/01/26/api-version-sc-s-m15.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RICOH THETA WebAPI Versions" /><published>2021-01-26T05:22:40-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-26T05:22:40-08:00</updated><id>https://codetricity.github.io/sc2-public-code-examples/api/versions,/s,/m15,/sc/2021/01/26/api-version-sc-s-m15</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codetricity.github.io/sc2-public-code-examples/api/versions,/s,/m15,/sc/2021/01/26/api-version-sc-s-m15.html">&lt;p&gt;There are three versions of the WebAPI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;API v1 - PTP over TCP/IP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;API v2 - OSC protocol with sessionID&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;API v2.1 - OSC protocol without sessionID. Images can be downloaded by URI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specific THETA model support is documented on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.ricoh/docs/theta-api-introduction/&quot;&gt;THETA API Introduction&lt;/a&gt; on the RICOH Developer Connection site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021_01/api_versions.png&quot; alt=&quot;api versions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most cameras, including the S, SC, V, SC2, SC2, and Z1 use the v2.1 API specification.  This API is easier to
use as it does not require specifying a session ID.  Images on the camera can be downloaded with a simple
GET call to the URI of the image.  You can get the URI of the images from listImages.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="API" /><category term="versions," /><category term="s," /><category term="m15," /><category term="sc" /><summary type="html">There are three versions of the WebAPI. API v1 - PTP over TCP/IP API v2 - OSC protocol with sessionID API v2.1 - OSC protocol without sessionID. Images can be downloaded by URI. The specific THETA model support is documented on the THETA API Introduction on the RICOH Developer Connection site. Most cameras, including the S, SC, V, SC2, SC2, and Z1 use the v2.1 API specification. This API is easier to use as it does not require specifying a session ID. Images on the camera can be downloaded with a simple GET call to the URI of the image. You can get the URI of the images from listImages.</summary></entry></feed>